Mohammed Nabil Chaudhary

Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates



mnabilchaudhary@gmail.com



+971504127153



linkedin.com/in/mohammed-nabilchaudhary-84924b1ba

Summary

I am quick on my feet and can pick up on concepts quickly. I am not afraid to try new things and push my skills to their limits.

I have been studying HTML, CSS, XML for around seven years now, Java, and SQL for five years, and I learned JavaScript, PHP, AJAX, MongoDB three years ago, and JavaFX four years ago.

I self-learned C and C++ three years ago, GDScipt- a Game Development language for the platform Godot. I also self-learned Phaser-a JavaScript-based library for Game Development and Aseprite- A Pixel Art Tool for a year now.

Experience



Research And Development Intern

The Assembly | Make Smart Things | Apr 2022 - Present (2 months +)

Freelance Web Developer

Fiverr Freelancers (Buyer and Seller) Feb 2021 - Oct 2021 (9 months)

Freelance Web Developer

FlogApp | One-App for All Services in UAE Jan 2021 - Oct 2021 (10 months)

Freelance Web Developer

Works

Feb 2021 - Jul 2021 (6 months)

Education



Middlesex University Dubai

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Technology

Sep 2019 - Apr 2022

In my first year, I studied HTML, CSS, XML, Java, JavaFX, SQL. I also learned about Ardunio, ML and Al Theory, and Recommender Systems Theory.

In my second year, I studied Javascript, PHP on top of advanced HTML and CSS, including DOM, JSON, Javascript Animation, Event Handling, etc. I also studied AJAX, Session Management, File Upload, Basket, Recommendation using JS, and some of the basics of other Libraries and Frameworks like jQuery, jQuery UI, Bootstrap, AngularJS, TypeScript.

In the Third Year, I learned more in-depth about AI and ML, both theory and practical. I also learned Web-Based Mobile Application Development. I learned the theory of User Experience. For my Final Year Project, I learned more about Game Development and Pixel Art using GDScript and Aseprite, by making a short game called "World Unknown".

I also learned Project Management and Data Management where I learned tools like Weka, Tableau, and Wireshark for Data Management.



Abu Dhabi Indian School

High School Diploma, Commerce, Information Technology I coded a Comic Book Shop in Java and MySQL for my 12th-grade final project.

Skills

Project Management • Research • Programming • Game Development • Creative Writing • Web Development • Software Development